MD. RAISUL ISLAM

Address: S/O:- Md. Nazrul Islam,

Vill:- Melghar, P.O:-Ashiya, P.S:- Patiya, Dist:-Chittagong.

Mobile: +8801814347485 (Personal) /+8801972328280 (Official).

E-mail ID: sazidcu@gmail.com



Career Objective:

To contribute in a promising organization where I can integrate my knowledge, skill and experience to add value of that organization and explore my potentials.

Career Summary:

I have completed my post-graduation from Chittagong University in 2008 & working in an renowned MNC, i.e., CEAT AKKHAN LTD. as "Area Manager – Sales & Marketing Dept." from July 02, 2016 to till now. Before that I have worked in PARTEX STAR GROUP as an "Area Sales Manager" from 01.06.2015 to 30.06.2016 in Chittagong region. I have also worked in T.K. Group of Industries, as an "Area Sales Manager" form 01.02.2014 to 19.05.2015 and I have also worked in an UAE based organization named as RAK Paints (PVT.) Ltd. as a Jr. Sales Officer from 10.04. 2011 to 31.01.2014.

Special Qualification:

I have strong academic & practical knowledge. And I can do perform my duties under pressure.

Employment History:

Total Year of Experience: 9 Year(s) Continuing.

1. <u>Area Manager – (Corporate & Dealer Sales) (July 02, 2016 – Continuing).</u> CEAT AKKHAN LTD.

Company Location: Shanta Western Tower, Level # 8, Bir Uttam Mir Shawkat Road, 186 Tejgaon I/A, Dhaka- 1208.

Department: Sales

Work Station: - Chittagong Region.

Duties/Responsibilities:

My main job responsibilities are given below.

- 1. To make sales plan for achieving monthly & yearly budget.
- 2. Implement company's business policy.
- 3. Ensure sales target and minimize overdue.
- 4. Maintain good relation with existing and new client.
- 5. To make plan as the annual budget achieved, etc.

2. Area Sales Manager - (Retail & Distributor Sales) - (June 01, 2015 - June 30, 2016)

PARTEX STAR GROUP

Company Location: Shanta Western Tower, Level # 13, Bir Uttam Mir Shawkat Road, 186 Tejgaon I/A,

Dhaka- 1208.
Department: Sales

Work Station: - Chittagong Region.

Duties/Responsibilities:

My major job responsibilities are stated below.

- 1. To ensure products in maximum number of outlet under the assigned area to sell products.
- 2. Increase targeted number of dealers to sell all products in the region.
- 3. Ensure dealers satisfaction & motivation with the service of the respective executive.
- 4. To execute daily sales call on time & effectively trough all sales executive.
- 5. Ensure proper call report from field force as well within the time.
- 6. Plan and execute the targeted sales to achieve as per day /week & month.
- 7. Ensure on time collection from all dealers under the region & endure zero overdue.
- 8. Analyze market size of each product, plan for to get the market share & inform to the management.
- 9. Execute promotional plan & branding activities as per guideline.

3. Area Sales Manager- (Retail & Distributor Sales)- (February 01, 2014 - May 19, 2015)

T.K. Group of Industries

Company Location: T.K. Bhaban (2nd Floor), 13, Kawran Bazar, Dhaka - 1215.

Department: Pusti Consumer Division

Work Station:- Dhaka Region.

Duties/Responsibilities:

My major job responsibilities are stated below.

- 1. Maintaining and increasing sales of my company's products.
- 2. Reaching the targets and goals set for my area.
- 3. Establishing, maintaining and expanding my customer base.
- 4. Servicing the needs of my existing customers.
- 5. Increasing business opportunities through various routes to market.
- 6. Setting sales targets for individual reps and my team as a whole.
- 7. Recruiting and training sales staff.
- 8. Allocating areas to sales representatives.
- 9. Developing sales strategies and setting targets.
- 10. Monitoring my team's performance and motivating them to reach targets.
- 11. Compiling and analyzing sales figures.
- 12. Possibly dealing with some major customer accounts myself.
- 13. Collecting customer feedback and market research.

- 14. Reporting to senior managers.
- 15. Finally, Keeping up to date with products and competitors.

4. Jr. Sales Officer - (Corporate & Dealer Sales)- (April 10, 2011 - January 31, 2014)

RAK Paints (Pvt.) Ltd.

Company Location: Uttara, Sector # 4, Jasim Uddin Sharak, Dhaka.

Department: Sales

Work Station:- Chittagong & Cox'sbazar Region.

Duties/Responsibilities:

The major responsibilities are that followings.

- 1. To generate sales.
- 2. To create new and potential customer.
- 3. To create new dealer and handling the existing dealers also.
- 4. To visit new and old project and also dealer point.
- 5. To maintain the collection schedule.
- 6. To achieve the sales target.
- 7. To maintain daily call report.
- 8. To give information about the market competitor's activities to the management.
- 9. Finally to implement the strategic plan of the company so that company's goal achieved.

Academic Qualification:

Exam Title	Concentration/Major	Institute	Result	Pas.Year	Duration	Achievement
MBA	Human Resource Management	University of Chittagong	CGPA:3.66 out of 4	2008	1 year	A-
BBA	Management Studies/Science	University of Chittagong	CGPA:3.49 out of 4	2007	4 Years	B+
HSC	Science	Patiya Govt. College	Second Division, Marks :50%	2002	2 years	Second Division
SSC	Science	Jangal Khain High School	First Division, Marks :63%	2000	2 years	First Division

Training Summary:

Training Title	Topic	Institute	Country	Location	Year	Duration
Workshop on Food Crisis in the world	World Food Crisis	Chittagong University Management Students Club.	Bangladesh	Chittagong	2009	1 Day
Workshop on Banking as a Career.	Career in Banking.	Chittagong University Management Students Club.	Bangladesh	Chittagong	2009	1 Day
Workshop on Debating	Debating	Chittagong University Debating Society	Bangladesh	Chittagong	2008	1 Day

Professional Qualification:

Certification	Institute	Location	From	То
Diploma in Computer Studies	Chittagong City Corporation Computer Institute	Chittagong	March 11, 2007	September 11, 2007

Extra Curricular Activities:

I like playing Cricket & Catching fish, Watching TV and Listening music in my leisure time. And I always try to engage myself in different voluntary work for society.

Language Proficiency:

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
Bangla	High	High	High
English	High	High	High

Personal Details:

Father's Name : Nazrul Islam Mother's Name : Saju nur

Date of Birth : October 03, 1984

Gender : Male

Marital Status : Married

Nationality : Bangladeshi

National Id No. : 1516115549486

Religion : Islam

Permanent Address S/O:- Nazrul Islam (Badsha Ali Shikder Bari),Vill. Melghar, P.O. Ashiya, P.S.

Patiya, Dist:- Chittagong.

Current Location : Chittagong

Reference (s):

Reference: 01 Reference: 02

O. R. Nizam Road, GEC, Chittagong.

Name : Kazi Md. Mainuddin Sayem Dr. Md. Faridul Alam

Organization : CEAT AKKHAN LTD. | Chattagram Metropolitan Hospital

Designation : Head of Sales & Marketing Director

Shanta Western Tower, Level # 8,

Address : Bir Uttam Mir Shawkat Road, 186

Tejgaon I/A Dhaka- 1208.

Email Id : sayem.mainuddin@ceatbd.com

Mobile : 01972328251 01817206099

Relation : Reporting Line Manager. Maternal Uncle.

(Md. Raisul Islam)